Finding Aid for the Ralph Edwards Productions Production Records PASC.0336
UCLA Library Special Collections
- This is Your Life, 1952-1987; Series 1.
  - Research Material, Scripts and Sound Recordings, Subseries 1.
    - Tennessee Ernie Ford, 1956 December 12 (Box 236)
      Subject is a film and recording star. Guests include: Cliffie Stone, his manager, Western bandleader, radio and TV star.
    - Hal Foster, 1954 April 14 (Box 229)
      Subject is the "Prince Valiant" comic strip artist. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Brian Aherne, actor; Charles F. Armstrong, fellow artist at Palenske-Young; does the lettering on "Prince Valiant" comic strip; Robert Jacks, film producer; Bradley Kelly, Vice President of King Features Syndicate; Janet Leigh, actress; Victor McLaglen, actor; Sydney Metcalfe, artist; Terry Moore, artist; Joseph H. Neebe, Vice President of Campbell-Ewald Advertising Agency; Debra Paget, actress; Paul Proehl, animator; Robert Wagner, actor.
    - Connie Francis, 1961 January 15 (Box 229)
      Subject is a singer. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Dick Clark, TV personality; Bobby Darin, singer, actor; Arnold Maxin, President of MGM Records; Juliet Prowse, actress, dancer; Gil Roden, television producer; George Scheck, business manager.
    - Arthur Franz, 1953 April 1 (Box 229)
      Subject is a film and television star. Includes: script; research notes.
    - William Frawley, 1961 January 6 (Box 229)
      Subject is a film and television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Lucille Ball, actress; Tim Considine, actor; Don Fedderson, producer of TV show "My Three Sons"; Don Grady, actor; Fred Haney, general manager of Los Angeles Angels (newest American League baseball team); Erskine Johnson, Hollywood columnist for the Newspaper Enterprises Association; Eugenie Leontovich, actress; Stanley Livingston, actor; Fred MacMurray, actor; Walter Meyer, his agent; Edna Louise Mueller, ex-wife and former vaudeville partner.
    - Joe Frazier, 1971 July 29 (Box 229)
      Subject is a World Heavyweight Champion. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: boxers Muhammad Ali, Hans Huber, Archie Moore, Sugar Ray Robinson; Jack Stevenson, sportswriter with Associated Press; Jim Murray, sportswriter with L.A. Times; Tom Hawkins, former basketball player, now sportscaster with KNBC-TV, L.A.; Bud Furillo, Sports Editor of L.A. Herald Examiner; Yancey "Yank" Durham, manager; Eamonn Andrews, host of English TIYL.
    - Harold French, 1970 May 13 (Box 225)
    - Admiral Samuel Fuqua, 1958 December 3 (Box 229)
      Subject is a Pearl Harbor hero. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Guy Gabaldon, 1957 June 19 (Box 229)
      Subject is a Marine war hero. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Joe Galbreath, 1949 April 12; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is an Oklahoma rancher. Includes: script, research notes, audio. Guests include: Cal Tinney, Western humorist (radio, movies, newspaper columns); has NBC TV show "Stop Me If You've Heard This One" out of NYC - also worked on "Oologah Oozings"; Jimmy Wakely, singer, actor, cowboy star; Dal Walker, cowboy.
    - Dr. George H. Gale, 1957 March 20 (Box 229)
      Subject is a country doctor. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Bill Leyden, host of TV's "It Could Be You".
    - James Garner, 1958 June 25 (Box 229)
      Subject is a television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Richard Bare, film director, one of the directors of subject's TV show "Maverick" - hired subject for small parts in TV show "Cheyenne"; Jack Bumgarner, brother, was baseball player, former pitcher with Pittsburgh Pirates; Jack Casey, Warner Brothers publicity man; Paul Gregory, stage and movie producer; Elmer Holloway, NBC photographer; Jack Kelly, actor; Bill Leyden, host of TV's "It Could Be You", summer replacement for TIYL; William T. Orr, Executive producer for Warner Brothers Television Division; Fran Wood, TIYL staffer.
    - Rocky Gattellari, 1977 July 29 (Box 220)
    - Jock Geddes, 1976 July 2 (Box 220)
    - Jack Geene, 1949 June 7; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is an Episcopal minister fighting multiple sclerosis. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - Kathy Lee Gifford, 1993 November 23 (Box 229)
      Subject is a talk show host, and singer. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Lennon Sisters, singing group; Ralph Edwards, Larry Gatlin, Country singer; with subject on TV's "Hee Haw"; Sam Haskell, agent; Regis Philbin, TV personality; Neil Sedaka, musician and songwriter; Chris Tardio, Producer on "Good Morning America".
    - Emma Crooks Gilbert, 1950 April 12 (Box 217)
      Subject is a minister's wife. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Emma Crooks Gilbert, 1950 April 12; streaming audio (Box 229)
      Subject is a minister's wife. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - Wolfe Gilbert, 1949 January 18; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is a song writer. Includes: script, research notes, audio. Guests include: Harry Akst, songwriter ("Am I Blue?", "Dinah"); Abel Baer, songwriter, with subject co-wrote "Lucky Lindy" (before Lindbergh left on flight) and "My Mother's Eyes"; Gene Buck, former president of ASCAP; Eddie Cantor, entertainer; Al Comparte, music publisher; Walda Donaldson, widow of late composer Walter Donaldson; Mabel (Mrs. Nick Campbell) Wayne, composed music for "Ramona" (subject wrote lyric).
    - Hermione Gingold, 1961 April 19 (Box 229)
      Subject is an English comedienne of the stage, film and television. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Jack Benny, comedian; Walter Crisham, actor; Morton Da Costa, film director ("The Music Man" in which subject appears); Billie De Wolfe, actor (Broadway, movies, TV, supper clubs), co-starred with subject in "John Murray Anderson's Almanac" on Broadway; Roy Dean, actor; Gretchen Franklin, actress; Charles Hickman, stage director ("Sweet & Low" was his first directorial assignment in London theatre); Stephen Joseph, son, director of the Theatre-in-the-Round in England.
    - Hermione Gingold, 1961 April 23 (Box 236)
      Subject is an English comedienne of the stage, film and television.
    - Else Giorgi, 1984 May 20 (Box 229)
      Subject is a doctor to celebrities and inner-city patients. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Robert Bigonnet, runs La Chardonnay restaurant; James Caan, actor, director; Florence Henderson, actress; Quincy Jones, composer, music producer; Joan Rivers, comedienne; Johnie Scott, member of "Sons of Watts."
    - Edna Gladney, 1953 December 17 (Box 229)
      Subject founded a child adoption home. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Greer Garson, actress.
    - Jimmie Gleason, 1958 January 8 (Box 230)
      Subject is a film star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Robert Armstrong, actor; Tom Brown, actor; Lou Sherrell, agent.
    - Sadie Glommen, 1958 November 19 (Box 230)
      Subject is the mother of seven in Service. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Marion Robbins Goldwyn, 1949 November 16; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Polio story. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - Jack Good, 1970 March 18 (Box 225)
    - Reverend Clinton Goodwin, 1960 June 1 (Box 230)
      Subject is an ex-convict, now minister. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Ruth Gordon, 1971 September 29 (Box 230)
      Subject is a film star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Dame Judith Anderson, actress; Beulah Bondi, actress; Bud Cort, actor; Bob Goodfried, Head of publicity for Paramount; Garson Kanin, husband, actor, playwright, producer, director, author; Madge Kennedy, actress - one of Samuel Goldwyn's original five silent movie stars; Raymond Massey, actor; Natalie Wood, actress.
    - Walter Gordon, 1950 April 5; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is the Chairman of the California Adult Authority Board. Includes: script, research notes, audio. Guests include: Gov. Earl Warren, Governor of California.
    - Chester Gould, 1958 October 22 (Box 230)
      Subject is the creator of "Dick Tracy." Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: George Florey, advertising executive; Ray Gould, brother, has worked on "Dick Tracy" comic strip with subject since 1945; Don Malmberg, and n McClintock, TIYL staffers; Howard Ross, NBC executive.
    - Billy Graham, 1957 November 13 (Box 230)
      Subject is an evangelist. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Richard Nixon, U.S. Vice President.
    - Stanley Graham, 1977 February 25 (Box 220)
    - Virginia Graham, 1956 February 15 (Box 230)
      Subject is a dancer and television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Harry Guttenberg, husband, president of Lewis Guttenberg and Sons, Theatrical Costumers; Jack Housman, Vice Chairman of the Board of the United Cerebral Palsy Association.
    - Johnny Grant, 1960 December 7 (Box 230)
      Subject is the disc jockey, "The Mayor of Hollywood." Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Roscoe Ates, was the original "Sad Sack" of the Armed Forces; Bob Hope, entertainer; Herman Joseph, circus clown with the Mills Brothers Circus; Major Jimmy Lynch, Jr., son of man who owned traveling show (The Jimmy Lynch Death Dodgers) that hired subject as announcer; with Army, works at the Pentagon; Jayne Mansfield, actress; Richard Nixon, U.S. Vice President; Debbie Reynolds, actress; Penny Singleton, actress; Connie Stevens, singer, actress.
    - Al Grassby, 1977 February 4 (Box 220)
    - Peter Graves, 1971 January 17 (Box 230)
      Subject is a film and television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Peter Maxwell, director of TV show "Whiplash"; Greg Morris, actor; Jack Smight, film and television director.
    - Gilda Gray, 1954 June 23 (Box 230)
      Subject is a stage star who is also a tuberculosis victim. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Liberace, entertainer, pianist; Betty Compson, actress; Fifi D'Orsay, actress; W. C. Handy, songwriter; Sophie Tucker, singe.
    - Gilda Gray, 1954 June 23 (Box 236)
      Subject is a stage star who is also a tuberculosis victim.
      Annotated scripts (2).
    - Sylvan Greene, 1948 December 7; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is the co-pilot of the first plane fired upon at Pearl Harbor. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - George Gregory, Jr., 1955 June 8 (Box 230)
      Subject is the New York City Civil Service Commissioner. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Paul Williams, African-American architect; Sadie Knight, soprano concert singer.
    - Rev. Andy Griffin, 1954 January 6 (Box 81)
      Subject is a former con-man turned minister. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Andy Griffith, 1971 February 23 (Box 81)
      Subject is a film and television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Ken Berry, actor; James Oliver Brown, literary agent for Mac Hyman (author of "No Time for Sergeants"); Hal Cook, former national sales manager for Capitol Records, now publisher of Billboard Magazine; Ron Howard, actor; Elia Kazan, movie director; Sheldon Leonard, television producer; Richard Linke, manager, former Capitol Records promo man who helped sign subject; Jim Nabors, singer, actor; Glenn Wallichs, Head of Capitol Records.
    - Jennie Grossinger, 1954 December 29 (Box 81)
      Subject is a resort and hotel operator and philanthropist. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Eddie Cantor, entertainer; Eddie Fisher, singer; Jackie Robinson, African-American baseball player with Brooklyn Dodgers; Father Fred Gehring, famous World War II chaplain - in charge of Catholic missions in China.
    - Hershel Gruenberg, 1949 January 11; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is a Republic Pictures employee who is also a polio victim. Includes: script, research notes, audio. Guests include: Dale Evans, actress; Mort Goodman, Executive with Republic Pictures; members of "Riders of the Purple Sage", Johnny Paul, Darryl Rice, Al Sloey, Foy Willing; Forrest Tucker, actor; Roy Rogers, Western singer and actor.
    - Robert Gunderson, 1950 January 4; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is a blind ham radio operator. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - Bob Hagen, 1948 October 19 (Box 217)
    - Mrs. Betty Hahn, 1960 March 23 (Box 81)
      Subject is a mother who overcame adversity. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Herbert Hahn, son, was child actor on Broadway in show "Me and Molly"; Pauline Hahn, daughter, was regular for 10 years on "Horn & Hardart Children's Hour", known as the "Sweetheart of the East Side"; Harry Moss, Vice President of the National Council to Combat Blindness (Fight for Sight).
    - Connie Haines, 1954 February 24 (Box 81)
      Subject is a singer. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Fred Allen, legendary comedian (radio, film and TV personality); Tommy Dorsey, bandleader, musician (trombone player); Harry James, bandleader, musician (trumpet player); Peter Potter, TV personality.
    - Connie Haines, 1954 February 24 (Box 236)
    - Ken G. Hall, 1977 June 21 (Box 220)
    - Eddie Hamilton, 1955 January 26 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Chicago cab driver. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Maurine Hannah, 1950 February 22; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject was selected by telephone call at random. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - Lester Hansen, 1947 October 6 (Box 217)
      "This is Your Life" audition show.
    - Bill Harmon, 1977 June 10 (Box 220)
    - David Hartman, 1972 August 23 (Box 81)
      Subject is a television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: San Francisco Giants Bobby Bonds, Don Carrithers, Tito Fuentes, Al Gallagher, Juan Marichal, Willie McCovey, Sam McDowell, Frank Reberger, Chris Speier, Steve Stone; Horace Stoneham, President of the San Francisco Giants baseball team; Herb Steinberg, Head of public relations for Universal Tours; E. G. Marshall, actor; Jerry Lewis, actor, comedian; Jerry Herman, composer of "Hello, Dolly".
    - Phil Harris, 1957 September 25 (Box 81)
      Subject is a film star and musician. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Jack Benny, comedian; Bob Cobb, owner of Brown Derby; Joe Frisco, comedian; Alice Faye (Mrs. Phil) Harris, actress; radio and movie star; Minna Wallis, former manager, later top movie agent.
    - Randall Harris, 1958 January 2 (Box 81)
      Subject is a teacher, and war hero. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Randall Harris, 1958 January 22 (Box 236)
      Subject is a teacher, and war hero.
    - Rolf Harris, 1977 January 25 (Box 220)
    - Pro Hart, 1976 August 6 (Box 220)
    - Jonah Hatfield, 1948 November 16; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is a pioneer who participated in the 1893 Oklahoma land rush. Includes:script, research notes, audio.
    - Mary Healy, 1953 June 24 (Box 81)
      Subject is a film, stage and television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Grace Hayes, famous vaudevillian, singer; Peter Lind Hayes, husband, actor, mimic; Lou Irwin, business manager; Dorothy Lamour, actrress; Audrey Stark, owner of the Star Modeling Agency.
    - J. Harrison Heckman, 1956 February 29 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Red Cross executive. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Ramond Eaton, Vice President of the American Red Cross; President Dwight D. Eisenhower.
    - Van Heflin, 1955 May 25 (Box 81)
      Subject is a film star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Chief Ben American Horse, head of the Sioux Nation; Don Dillaway, actor; Spike Jones, comedy bandleader, actor, TV host.
    - Sir Robert Helpmann, 1975 September 19 (Box 220)
    - James B. Hendryx, 1956 May 23 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Michigan outdoor sportsman. Includes: script; research notes.
    - William Hennessey, 1956 February 1 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Boston policeman. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Selma Herbert, 1959 December 16 (Box 81)
      Subject is a WAC Major. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Selma Herbert, 1959 December 16 (Box 236)
      Subject is a WAC Major.
    - Jean Hersholt, 1954 April 28 (Box 81)
      Subject is a film and radio star, and a humanitarian. Includes; script; research notes. Guests include: Frank Borzage, movie director, former actor; Rosemary DeCamp, actress; Frederick R. Goff, Chief of the Rare Books Division of the Library of Congress; Lilli Anne Leighton, former silent movie star, resident of the Motion Picture Country House; there to represent the many film workers helped by the Motion Picture Relief Fund (subject has been President of the Fund since 1938).
    - Bela Herskovits, 1956 February 8 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Cantor. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Eddie Cantor, legendary entertainer; Dr. Franz Nagy, Ex-Prime Minister of Hungary; Joseph Pasternak, film producer; Sen. Alexander Smith, U.S. Senator from New Jersey.
    - Cantor Bela Herskovits, 1956 February 8 (Box 236)
      Subject is a Cantor.
    - Col. Dean Hess, 1956 October 17 (Box 81)
      Subject is a fighter pilot and minister who assisted Korean War orphans. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Charlton Heston (Box 81)
      Subject is an actor and movie star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: David Bradley, film producer; Yakima Canutt, Academy Award winning stunt coordinator; Frazier Heston, son, screenwriter on "Mountain Men"; Walter Seltzer, film producer; Jack Valenti, President of the Motion Picture Association of America; Orson Welles, film director and actor; Dr. L. J. "Jolly" West, Chairman of the Psychiatry Department at UCLA.
    - Conrad Hilton, 1958 June 4 (Box 81)
      Subject is a hotel magnate. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Benny Hochman, 1961 January 5 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Polish displaced person. script; research notes. Guests include: former Presidents of the Hollywood Junior Chamber of Commerce, Lee Francis and Dr. Gil Gagos.
    - Bob Hope, 1970 November 17 (Box 225)
      Subject is a comdian and film star. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Constance Hope, 1957 February 6 (Box 63)
      Subject is a celebrity publicist. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Her Highness, the Begum Aga Khan, French wife of the imam of the Ismaili sect of Shiite Muslims and former prince in India before the British left; Rose Bampton, dramatic soprano with the Metropolitan Opera; Fannie Hurst, writer; Lotte Lehmann, soprano with the Metropolitan Opera; Dr. Arthur Lelyveld, Executive Vice President of the America-Israel Cultural Foundation; Lauritz Melchior, tenor with the Metropolitan Opera; Robert Merrill, baritone, famous for his roles with the Metropolitan Opera; Gregory Ratoff, film director.
    - Robert Horton, 1961 January 18 (Box 63)
      Subject is a television star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Alan Livingstone, former Vice President in charge of programs for the Pacific Division of NBC, now Vice President of Capitol Records; Allan Miller, Vice President of Revue Studios; Peter Pritchard, Representative of the Leslie Grade Agency (large theatrical booking agency in England); Robert Walker, friend from college (UCLA); was casting director for Revue Productions, brought in subject to test for role on "Wagon Train"; now associate producer in charge of casting at Tandem Productions.
    - Lee Howard, 1950 May 9; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is an adventurer and pioneer. Includes: script, research notes, audio. Guests include: Robert Ormond Case, famous novelist and short story writer.
    - Oscar Howe, 1960 April 6 (Box 81)
      Subject is a Native American artist. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Chief Ben American Horse, Sioux tribal leader; Chief Howard Bad Bear, Sioux (Ogalala) tribal leader; Chief Frank Kicking Bear, Sioux (Minnicounjou) tribal leader; Vincent Price, Actor, art expert, member of the Indian Arts and Crafts Board of the Department of the Interior; Chief John Saul, Sioux (Yanktonai) tribal leader; Chief Iron (Gus) Shell Necklace, Sioux (Brule) tribal leader; Chief Henry Weasel, Sioux (Ogalala) tribal leader.
    - Father B. Hubbard, 1958 April 30 (Box 81)
      Subject is an explorer. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Rock Hudson, 1952 December 17 (Box 63)
      Subject is a film star. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Piper Laurie, actress; Frankie Van, referee and physical director, now at Universal-International Studios; Henry Willson, personal manager.
    - Dick Hughes, 1971 September 24 (Box 81)
      Subject provided aid to Saigon orphans. Includes: script; research notes.
    - Ted Husing, 1957 May 8 (Box 251)
      Subject is a sports announcer. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Maj. Felix "Doc" Blanchard, former Army football player at West Point, three time All-American; now assistant coach at West Point; Mickey Cochrane, baseball player; Glenn Davis, assistant director of special events (PR rep) for the L.A. Times newspaper; James Dolan, executive producer of sports for CBS Radio; Elyse Knox (Mrs. Tom) Harmon, actress; Tom Harmon, Sports Director of the Columbia Pacific Network, sportscaster; Eleanor Holm, Olympic swimmer, professional star of the Aquacade at the New York World's Fair; Harry Kipke, President of the Coca-Cola Bottling Company of Chicago; Guy Lombardo, musician, bandleader; Alice Marble, tennis champ; Jesse Owens, Olympic track Gold medalist; Dr. J. Andrew White, former President of CBS and subject's mentor - now a consulting psychologist in Hollywood.
    - Graeme Irvine, 1976 March 26 (Box 220)
    - Paul Jackson, 1948 November 9; streaming audio (Box 217)
      Subject is a paraplegic World War II veteran. Includes: script, research notes, audio.
    - Paul Jackson, 1948 November 9 (Box 236)
      Subject is a paraplegic World War II veteran.
    - Eddie Janis, 1953 April 29 (Box 251)
      Subject is a music publisher. Includes: script; research notes. Guests include: Phil Baker, comedian, accordion player, radio personality; member of vaudeville team with MacDaniel and subject 1913; Bobby Burns, songwriter; George Cates, songwriter; Carl Haverlin, President of BMI; George Howe, songwriter; Rene Chaplow (Mrs. Eddie) Janis, wife, also vaudevillian; Ed Kay, Musical Director of Monogram Pictures; Mel Leven, songwriter; Marion MacDaniel, member of vaudeville team with Phil Baker and subject in 1913; songwriters, Jack Owens, Henry Pritchard, Leo Robin, Robert Sour; Morris Stoloff, Musical Director of Columbia Pictures, two-time Academy Award winner; Merritt Tompkins, former Vice President of BMI.
    - Bill Johnson, 1984 March 17 (Box 251)
      Subject is an Olympic gold medalist. Includes an annotated script and production notes.
      Host: Joe Campanella.
    - Rafer Johnson, 1961 May 28 (Box 236)
      Subject is an Olympic gold medalist. Guests include: Dave Cantor, public relations man with 20th Century Fox; Elvin "Ducky" Drake, track coach and head trainer at UCLA; trainer of the 1956 U.S. Olympic team; Jim Johnson, member of the UCLA track team; George Sherman, film producer and director; Don Shinnick, athlete (football player; linebacker for Baltimore Colts); was student chairman of Campus Crusade for Christ at UCLA when subject was on Executive Committee.
      Annotated script. UCLA ties.
    - Rafer Johnson, 1961 May 28 (Box 251)
    - Mrs. Ruth Joiner, 1956 April 11 (Box 252)
      Subject is an Indiana schoolteacher. Includes script and research notes.
    - Carolyn Jones, 1959 December 30 (Box 252)